<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Topics: HCI | M Haidar Hanif | Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://mhaidarhanif.org/blog/topics/hci/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mhaidarhanif.org/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-13T21:25:09+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://mhaidarhanif.org/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[M Haidar Hanif]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[mhaidarhanif@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Metro Group's Future Store Initiative: The Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://mhaidarhanif.org/blog/metro-group-future-store-review/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-13T13:00:23+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://mhaidarhanif.org/blog/metro-group-future-store-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Innovation Background</h1>

<p>Innovative technology in human-computer interaction world has also come and rapidly changing on how people do business. One of the significant change is in technology shop, convenience store, or retail industry. That is, a huge chance in making huge change in order to develop it better and have the advantage of it.</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="http://future-store.org/internet/site/ts_fsi/resourceCached/1392658964150/common/img/header/logo.gif">http://future-store.org/internet/site/ts_fsi/resourceCached/1392658964150/common/img/header/logo.gif</a>" title="[METRO GROUP Logo [Metro Group Logo]]" >
One of the most popular or viral concept and implementation is <a href="http://future-store.org">Future Store Initiative</a> by Metro Group. Metro Group (Metro AG) is a German global diversified retail company and wholesale/cash and carry group based in Düsseldorf. We can compare them with <a href="http://carrefour.com">Carrefour</a>, another popular retail company.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>The METRO GROUP Future Store Initiative is a joint project including more than 75 partners from the retailing and consumer goods, IT and service sectors. Together, the initiative’s partners are driving forward the modernization process in the retailing sector. Each company brings something different to the project, depending on its sector and area of expertise: some make innovative technology available while others test the technology in practice. On top of that, all partners offer their expertise on managing processes more efficiently and improving services in the retailing sector. The METRO GROUP Future Store Initiative has succeeded in pooling the expertise of all its partners and using this knowledge to develop ground-breaking concepts. That makes the initiative a unique project.</p><footer><strong>Future Store Initiative</strong> <cite>METRO GROUP</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>The future store is a new concepts hands on technology shop or supermarket category. Its core idea may resolve new challenges that bridge between electronic commerce and ordinary daily life shopping. Because these days, retail industry is undergoing massive changes. So some more factors and aspects have the important role to make it better for businesses and customers. There must be also a cooperation between retail, consumer goods, information technology, service sector, and others. Some huge number of partners are taking part in developing and testing its innovative technologies and real-world concepts. Partners with various companies such as MetSAP, Intel, IBM, Cisco Systems, Fujitsu, and others to make it so.</p>

<p>What Future Store Initiative offers?</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s watch the presentational and actual videos.</p>

<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/bV-4phC2rvU "></iframe></div>
&mdash; <a href="http://youtu.be/bV-4phC2rvU">Metro Future Stores (jogundosekun on YouTube)</a></p>

<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/rZzls3VH678 "></iframe></div>
&mdash; <a href="http://youtu.be/rZzls3VH678">real,&ndash; Future Store (Saksanjutut on YouTube)</a></p>

<h1>A Virtual Tour of the Future Store</h1>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://www.retail-square.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Real.jpg">http://www.retail-square.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Real.jpg</a>" title="&lsquo;real,&ndash; Future Store&rsquo; &lsquo;real,&ndash; Future Store front building&rsquo;" >
&mdash; <a href="">real,&ndash; Future Store (Retail Square Blog)</a></p>

<p>(Yes, &ldquo;real,&ndash;&rdquo; rather than &ldquo;Real&rdquo; it is.)</p>

<p>This is where that advance and real implementation of ubiquitous computing mostly takes place, the advanced computing concept where computing is actually everywhere and anywhere, in contrast to desktop computing. Because it occurs with any device, location, and format. Further than that, it also takes place in customer&rsquo;s home.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, since early 2013, the Future Store Initiative was already closed. So it was mostly only tested as an experiment. So the rest is just history. Anyway, let&rsquo;s see what they have designed, developed, and achieved.</p>

<h2>Future (Things)</h2>

<h3>Mobile Shopping Assistant (MSA)</h3>

<h3>Payment by Fingerprint</h3>

<h3>Smart Freezer with RFID</h3>

<h2>Interface</h2>

<p>Please noted that it was developed, released or opened at circa 2008. So the interface may just represents the functional aspect without the esthetics.</p>

<h2>Human-Computer Interaction</h2>

<p>&hellip;</p>

<h1>Another Real World Practice</h1>

<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/"></iframe></div>
&mdash; <a href="http://youtu.be/">Samsung (Samsung on YouTube)</a></p>

<h1>Conclusion</h1>

<p>The combination of innovative technology and services is truly a crucial factor for trade. They proven to increase efficiency in logistics and in warehouse management, whilst at the same time, giving an individual service and advanced special shopping experience for the customer.
Surround your pullquote like this {" text to be quoted "}
It may actually help and boost customer with shopping experience. It&rsquo;s easier and faster to scan, list, buy, and deliver goods that actually needed. Business happy. Customer happy. But in the other hand, if it mismatched with the user&rsquo;s behavior, the experience could actually break. That&rsquo;s why the actual implementation must meet or fulfill the exact specifications and requirements. Objectively speaking, still, any advancement in innovation and technology is essentially good and useful.</p>

<h1><abbr title="Too Long; Didn't Read">TL;DR</abbr></h1>

<p>The innovation and technology of futuristic store from Metro Group in the ubiquitous cloud computing era.</p>

<h1>Additional Links</h1>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Future_Store">https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Future_Store</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.retail-square.com/shops/real-future-store">http://www.retail-square.com/shops/real-future-store</a></li>
<li><a href="http://bbc.co.uk/news/business-12310809">http://bbc.co.uk/news/business-12310809</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>

