<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Topics: Commerce | M Haidar Hanif | Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://mhaidarhanif.org/blog//topics/commerce/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mhaidarhanif.org/blog//"/>
  <updated>2014-03-25T11:11:24+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://mhaidarhanif.org/blog//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[M Haidar Hanif]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[mhaidarhanif@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Metro Group's Future Store Initiative: The Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://mhaidarhanif.org/blog//metro-group-future-store-review/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-16T06:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://mhaidarhanif.org/blog//metro-group-future-store-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Innovation Background</h1>

<p>Innovative technology in human-computer interaction world has also come and rapidly changing on how people do business. One of the significant change is in technology shop, convenience store, or retail industry. That is, a huge chance in making huge change in order to develop it better and have the advantage of it.</p>

<p>{% img center <a href="http://www.weiterleitung.metrogroup.de/metrogroup_logo.gif">http://www.weiterleitung.metrogroup.de/metrogroup_logo.gif</a> &lsquo;METRO GROUP Logo&rsquo; %}
One of the most popular or viral concept and implementation is <a href="http://future-store.org">Future Store Initiative</a> by Metro Group. Metro Group (Metro AG) is a German global diversified retail company and wholesale/cash and carry group based in Düsseldorf. We can compare them with <a href="http://carrefour.com">Carrefour</a>, another popular retail company.</p>

<p>{% blockquote Future Store Initiative, METRO GROUP %}
The METRO GROUP Future Store Initiative is a joint project including more than 75 partners from the retailing and consumer goods, IT and service sectors. Together, the initiative’s partners are driving forward the modernization process in the retailing sector. Each company brings something different to the project, depending on its sector and area of expertise: some make innovative technology available while others test the technology in practice. On top of that, all partners offer their expertise on managing processes more efficiently and improving services in the retailing sector. The METRO GROUP Future Store Initiative has succeeded in pooling the expertise of all its partners and using this knowledge to develop ground-breaking concepts. That makes the initiative a unique project.
{% endblockquote %}</p>

<p>The future store is a new concepts hands on technology shop or super/hypermarket category. Its core idea may resolve new challenges that bridge between electronic commerce and ordinary dailyy life shopping. Because these days, retail industry is undergoing massive changes. So some more factors and aspects have the important role to make it better for businesses and customers. There must be also a cooperation between retail, consumer goods, information technology, service sector, and others. Some huge number of partners are taking part in developing and testing its innovative technologies and real-world concepts. Partners with various companies such as MetSAP, Intel, IBM, Cisco Systems, Fujitsu, and others to make it so.</p>

<p>What Future Store Initiative offers? What if every good technology combined together to make the ultimate commerce and retail system? We may discuss more on the realistic side rather than conceptual side.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Let&rsquo;s watch the presentational and actual videos. Or for actual readers, there&rsquo;s a white paper titled <a href="http://chainlinkresearch.com/parallaxview/whitepapers/Welcome_to_the_future_store.pdf">&ldquo;Welcome to the Future Store&rdquo; (PDF)</a>.</p>

<p>{% youtube bV-4phC2rvU %}
&ndash; <a href="http://youtu.be/bV-4phC2rvU">Metro Future Stores (jogundosekun on YouTube)</a></p>

<p>{% youtube rZzls3VH678 %}
&ndash; <a href="http://youtu.be/rZzls3VH678">real,- Future Store (Saksanjutut on YouTube)</a></p>

<h1>A Virtual Tour of the Future Store</h1>

<p>{% img <a href="http://www.wanzl.com/uploads/pics/Real_erfolgsgeschichte_FutureStore_540_web_01.jpg">http://www.wanzl.com/uploads/pics/Real_erfolgsgeschichte_FutureStore_540_web_01.jpg</a> 730 &lsquo;real,- Future Store front building&rsquo; %}
&ndash; <a href="http://wanzl.com/en_DE/company/success-stories/real-de.html">The real,- Future Store in Tönisvorst (Wanzl)</a></p>

<p>(Yes, &ldquo;real,-&rdquo; rather than &ldquo;Real&rdquo; it is.)</p>

<p>This is where that advance and real implementation of ubiquitous computing mostly takes place, the advanced computing concept where computing is actually everywhere and anywhere, in contrast to desktop computing. Because it occurs with any device, location, and format. Further than that, it also takes place in customer&rsquo;s home.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, since early 2013, the Future Store Initiative has already closed. So it was mostly only tested as an experiment. So the rest is just history. Anyway, let&rsquo;s see what they have designed, developed, and achieved.</p>

<h2>Future (Things)</h2>

<p>Let&rsquo;s take a journey in the future of retailing. Notice that these technologies work together simultaneously.</p>

<h3>Mobile Shopping Assistant (MSA)</h3>

<p>{% img <a href="http://newsimg.bbc.co.uk/media/images/40163000/jpg/_40163605_psa203m.jpg">http://newsimg.bbc.co.uk/media/images/40163000/jpg/_40163605_psa203m.jpg</a> &lsquo;MSA or PSA in Tablet PC&rsquo; %}
Or Personal Shopping Assistant (PSA) is the convenient, user-friendly computer on the shopping cart.</p>

<p>What it can do and we get?</p>

<ul>
<li>Greets the customer by name.</li>
<li>Displays information and prices when the customer scans the product barcode over the built-in reading device.</li>
<li>Provides information about special offers and promotions.</li>
<li>Directs the customer to the products he needs.</li>
<li>Keeps a running total of the shopping bill.</li>
<li>Makes check-out much faster, as the customer has already scanned their purchases while shopping.</li>
<li>The data transfer process triggered from the PSA to the checkout counter automatically.</li>
<li>The receipt is printed out and the customer then pays.</li>
<li>No need to take goods out of the shopping cart and no queue.</li>
</ul>


<p>So in short, it&rsquo;s smarter to shop and reduces waiting time. In addition, the customers need a Loyalty Card to use it.</p>

<p>According to the technical specifications from numerous partner services, it has:</p>

<ul>
<li>XGA pressure-sensitive touchscreen.</li>
<li>Built-in EAN barcode scanner.</li>
<li>Long battery life.</li>
<li>Operating system with special application software by Multichannel Retail.</li>
<li>Communicates with the store’s central data server via the internal WLAN network.</li>
<li>Central data server applications, based on database.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Electronic Advertising Displays (EAD)</h3>

<p>{% img <a href="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/6167/2089/320/FSI-Technologien_AdvertisingDisplays.jpg">http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/6167/2089/320/FSI-Technologien_AdvertisingDisplays.jpg</a> &lsquo;EAD in action&rsquo; %}
A dynamic display that reliable and always up-to-date. They help customers find their way around the store and latest special offers, also provide detailed information through videos or animations. They are centrally managed over the network through an internal wireless LAN connection. There&rsquo;s a chance that if it&rsquo;s presented like this, it could be more interesting.</p>

<h3>Information Terminals</h3>

<p>{% img <a href="http://newsimg.bbc.co.uk/media/images/40163000/jpg/_40163603_infoterminal203m.jpg">http://newsimg.bbc.co.uk/media/images/40163000/jpg/_40163603_infoterminal203m.jpg</a> &lsquo;Information Terminals&rsquo; %}
Or infoterminals. Like a computerized catalogs. They provide a wealth and details of information about all the products, even the manufacturing process, ingredients, and selling price. Also with additional useful household and health tips, such as recipes and tips. And obviously where to find  them.</p>

<h3>Electronic Price Labels</h3>

<p>{% img <a href="http://spectrum.ieee.org/images/apr04/images/0404nsuperf2.jpg">http://spectrum.ieee.org/images/apr04/images/0404nsuperf2.jpg</a> &lsquo;Electronic Price Labels&rsquo; %}
Officially called Electronic Shelf Labeling (ESL) System with digital LC displays, communicate through a separate wireless network using Communication Base Stations (CBS). So they&rsquo;re a far better accurate and always updated price labels. No this is one of the most useful and convenient way to put a price label.</p>

<h3>Intelligent Scales</h3>

<p>{% img <a href="http://newsimg.bbc.co.uk/media/images/40163000/jpg/_40163597_scale203m.jpg">http://newsimg.bbc.co.uk/media/images/40163000/jpg/_40163597_scale203m.jpg</a> &ldquo;IBM&rsquo;s Veggie Vision: Intelligent Scales&rdquo; %}
Automatically recognizes what type of food (fruit or vegetable) is being weighed, also look for the product symbol. So just place the product on the scale, then a label is automatically printed out. They&rsquo;re linked to the electronic point of sale (EPOS) controller via the store’s wireless network.</p>

<h3>Self Checkout</h3>

<p>{% img <a href="https://m1.behance.net/rendition/modules/4124267/disp/dcf80744ab7bfa2ab69c471b1717e4ea.jpg">https://m1.behance.net/rendition/modules/4124267/disp/dcf80744ab7bfa2ab69c471b1717e4ea.jpg</a> 360 &lsquo;FastLane checkout&rsquo; %}
{% img <a href="http://kantarretailiq.eu/Content/Render/508012.jpeg">http://kantarretailiq.eu/Content/Render/508012.jpeg</a> 360 &lsquo;Self checkout&rsquo; %}
<a href="https://www.behance.net/gallery/Future-Store-Initiative/707414">FastLane checkout branding by Mark Magnusson</a>
and
<a href="http://kantarretailiq.eu/Conversation/ConversationDetails.aspx?id=508014">Self checkout system</a></p>

<p>Simply swipe each item over the scanner and place it in a shopping bag. Then just pay with two payment options:</p>

<ul>
<li>Cash: bills or coins using the special cash terminal</li>
<li>Card: debit/credit card at the payment terminal.</li>
</ul>


<p>The details of each transaction to the store’s central POS controller, which transfers the sales data to the central Merchandise Management System (MMS).</p>

<h3>Personal Digital Assistant (PDA)</h3>

<p>{% img <a href="http://plstorebrands.com/images/plmag/pli_fall2003/features/1b.jpg">http://plstorebrands.com/images/plmag/pli_fall2003/features/1b.jpg</a> Employee&rsquo;s PDA %}
Not to be confused with MSA or PSA, of course. It&rsquo;s for the store employees. So they can communicate more flexibly and efficiently, access the merchandise management system, check stock levels anytime, examine each shelf to monitor expiration dates, and much more. Also yes, it&rsquo;s equipped with an RFID reader.</p>

<h3>Smart Shelves</h3>

<p>{% img <a href="http://newsimg.bbc.co.uk/media/images/40163000/jpg/_40163601_gilette_rfidbox203.jpg">http://newsimg.bbc.co.uk/media/images/40163000/jpg/_40163601_gilette_rfidbox203.jpg</a> &ldquo;Smart shelves with radio tags&rdquo; %}
{% img <a href="http://economists-pick-research.hktdc.com/resources/MI_Portal/Article/imn/2004/02/38561/retail089r.jpg">http://economists-pick-research.hktdc.com/resources/MI_Portal/Article/imn/2004/02/38561/retail089r.jpg</a> %}
The name explains themselves.</p>

<h3>Radio-Frequency Identification (RFID)</h3>

<p>RFID, RFID Reader, RFID transponder, RFID everywhere, and much more RFIDs. Almost all the above technologies and products use RFID. How it works in the context of Future Store? <a href="http://www.future-store.org/internet/site/ts_fsi/node/140064/Len/index.html">Read more in their site</a>. More into how it works can be <a href="http://electronics.howstuffworks.com/gadgets/high-tech-gadgets/rfid.htm">read in HowStuffWorks</a>.</p>

<p>Its areas of application includes:</p>

<ul>
<li>Product Transport: for METRO Group Distribution Logistics (MDL)</li>
<li>Warehouse Dispatch</li>
<li>Product Delivery</li>
<li>Storage in the Backstore</li>
<li>Transporting the Goods into the Store</li>
</ul>


<h3>More (Things)</h3>

<p>There are absolutely much more features beyond those.</p>

<p>{% img <a href="http://kantarretailiq.eu/Content/Render/508013.jpeg">http://kantarretailiq.eu/Content/Render/508013.jpeg</a> 225 300 &lsquo;Roger the Robot&rsquo; %}
{% img <a href="http://kantarretailiq.eu/Content/Render/508013.jpeg">http://kantarretailiq.eu/Content/Render/508013.jpeg</a> 225 300 &lsquo;Roger the Robot&rsquo; %}
{% img <a href="http://kantarretailiq.eu/Content/Render/508013.jpeg">http://kantarretailiq.eu/Content/Render/508013.jpeg</a> 225 300 &lsquo;Roger the Robot&rsquo; %}</p>

<ul>
<li>Robots. Yes, interesting.</li>
</ul>


<p>{% img <a href="http://www.spychips.com/metro/images/payback-card-large.jpg">http://www.spychips.com/metro/images/payback-card-large.jpg</a> 250 %}
&ndash; <a href="http://www.spychips.com/metro/scandal-payback.html">METRO&rsquo;s Loyalty Card</a></p>

<ul>
<li>Loyalty card with hidden RFID tag.</li>
<li>Wireless Information Highway.</li>
<li>Barcode.</li>
<li>Electronic Product Code (EPC).</li>
<li>(Serialized) Global Trade Item Number (S/GTIN).</li>
<li>Smart Freezer.</li>
<li>Logistic Unit.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Interface</h2>

<p>Please noted that it was developed, released or opened at circa 2003. So the interface may more represents the functional aspect with Web 2.0 design. This is the enhanced version of most common UI in the store.</p>

<p>{% img <a href="https://m1.behance.net/rendition/modules/4124263/disp/5d2dc9cf66926d500bc4523d041ff0cf.jpg">https://m1.behance.net/rendition/modules/4124263/disp/5d2dc9cf66926d500bc4523d041ff0cf.jpg</a> 730 Common Future Store UI %}
&ndash; <a href="https://www.behance.net/gallery/Future-Store-Initiative/707414">Future Store UI by Mark Magnusson</a></p>

<h1>Conclusion</h1>

<p>In human-computer interaction aspect, there&rsquo;re a lot of things connected together and going on here. The system mostly use ubiquitous computing to manage, set, arrange, and control all the equipment and tools, where human (customers, employees, and managers) who also interact more with the technology itself  experience the better shopping and retailing process.</p>

<p>The combination of various innovative technology and services is truly a crucial factor for trade. It proven to increase efficiency in logistics and in warehouse management, whilst at the same time, giving an individual service and advanced special shopping experience for the customer.
{% pullquote left %}
{&ldquo; So it still depends on consumer&rsquo;s taste and understanding. &rdquo;}
{% endpullquote %}
It may actually help and boost customer with shopping experience. It&rsquo;s easier and faster to scan, list, buy, and deliver goods that actually needed. Business happy. Customer happy. But in the other hand, if it mismatched with the user&rsquo;s behavior, the experience could actually break. That&rsquo;s why the actual implementation must meet or fulfill the exact specifications and requirements. Objectively speaking, still, any advancement in innovation and technology is essentially good and useful.</p>

<h1><abbr title="Too Long; Didn't Read">TL;DR</abbr></h1>

<p>The innovation and technology of futuristic store from Metro Group in the ubiquitous cloud computing era.</p>

<h1>Additional Links</h1>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Future_Store">Future Store – Wikipedia</a></li>
<li><a href="http://retail-square.com/shops/real-future-store">real,- Future Store | Super/hypermarket in Tönisvorst (DE)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://kantarretailiq.eu/Conversation/ConversationDetails.aspx?id=508014">Store of the Week: Real</a></li>
<li><a href="http://wanzl.com/en_DE/company/success-stories/real-de.html">Success stories - Real (DE)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.spychips.com/metro/scandal-payback.html">spychips | Scandal: The RFID Tag Hidden in METRO&rsquo;s Loyalty Card</a></li>
<li><a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/3712261.stm">The future of shopping by Tim Weber</a></li>
<li><a href="http://spectrum.ieee.org/computing/embedded-systems/supermarkets-futuristic-outlet">Supermarket&rsquo;s Futuristic Outlet by John Blau</a></li>
<li><a href="http://bbc.co.uk/news/business-12310809">BBC News - Is this the supermarket of the future?</a></li>
<li><a href="http://books.google.co.id/books?id=rM9cJVWiceYC">Retailing in the 21st Century: Current and Future Trends</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.behance.net/gallery/Future-Store-Initiative/707414">Future Store Initiative Design by Mark Magnusson</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>

